FELIKS KRUTSKO

krutsko44@gmail.com ► https://feliks.krutsko.net •

Professional Welder & Fitter

SUMMARY

I am a highly proficient **all-position** welder/fitter with over 20 years of experience in **GMAW** (MIG), **GTAW** (TIG), **SMAW** (Stick), and **FCAW** welding with a demonstrated specialization in welding **steel** and **stainless steel** with x-ray quality. My proven ability to read **blueprints** and **drawings** makes me an excellent asset in any work environment, and my **problem-solving** skills enable me to take on complex projects. Additionally, I am a team player who can train and manage personnel.

EXPERIENCE

TREMONTE MANUFACTURING & IRON WORKS LTD. | Welder/Fitter

2004 - Present

- Assembled, fabricated and welded beams, stairs and railings of all shapes and sizes
- Bolted, clamped and tack-welded parts to secure components prior to welding
- Applied knowledge of geometry and welding techniques to assist in manufacturing
- Ensured proper operation of equipment and material quality prior to fabrication
- Carried out routine maintenance and repairs on shop equipment and machinery
- Read blueprint and engineering drawings and created jigs to assist with assembly
- Performed structure fitting of final products to ensure compliance with blueprints
- Was present during installation to ensure final products met design specifications
- Ensured safety standards are followed according to CCOHS and WSIB principles
- Worked with minimal supervision and assisted supervisor in training of personnel

C ORE Architectural Metal Inc. | Welder/Fitter

2003 - 2004

- Performed assembly and welding of large structures including stairwells and railings
- Removed rough spots from work pieces with portable grinders, hand files and scrapers
- Worked closely with engineers to ensure the final product met design specifications

Progress Steel Fabricating & Welding Co. Ltd. | Welder/Fitter

2001 - 2003

- Assembled and welded underground tanks used for storage and sanitation purposes
- Examined the structure and texture of parts to detect imperfections and ensure quality

RIBAS BAKERY SYSTEMS INC. | Welder/Fitter

1999 - 2001

- Assembled conveyor systems for use in high-temperature food processing equipment
- Performed precision drilling and general fabrication conforming to product blueprints

EDUCATION

WELDING TRAINING DIPLOMA | Toronto Institute of Technical Trades **High School Diploma and WSIB, GTAW and FCAW Certificated**